I have a name for what happens to me.
Revival.
When it happens, I go back in time anywhere from one to five minutes.
And it always happens before something bad goes down.
I've managed to stop a lot of tragedies, so far.
Hey there, Satoru.
Hey, Mom.
Are you Satoru, Fujinuma?
You're gonna have to come down to the station.
Hmm.
Thank you.
See Maskman? Next week's the last episode.
I totally forgot to watch Black.
1988. February 15th?
Good morning, everyone.
Well, Satoru, you're gonna take your seat?
Huh? Oh. Yes, sir.
Where was my seat again?
You still asleep or something?
That's Kaio's desk, you doofus.
Oh, yeah.
No Kaio.
I'll have to mark her tardy again.
Satoru, are you, like, in love with Kaio?
You'd make a cute couple. You're both weird.
Here we go, folks.
Is this for real?
Why did I get dropped back to this time?
What's going on?
This is 18 years ago.
How far did you get on Dragon Quest 3?
Level 15.
That's it?
Nah, just testing.
I'm on 25.
You liar!
Hey, what's wrong?
Um, my head hurts, so I'm gonna see the nurse.
Then why are you taking your bag?
Don't worry about it.
I'll let the teacher know where you went.
What the hell's going on?
Is this revival?
I don't get it.
Why'd I go back this far?
Mom!
Hello.
Sorry to keep you waiting.
It's one of the neighbors.
That's right.
She'd be at work now.
Mom!
Hey there, kiddo.
Mom.
What's wrong?
Nothing. Just happy to see you.
You little weirdo.
So what do you want for dinner?
Hamburger or meatballs?
Uh, hamburger?
You getting hungry or what?
You're in a good mood.
Not like this morning when you pitched your little fit.
Guess you found your recorder, huh?
Yeah, I did.
I'm sorry.
It's nothing to cry about, kiddo.
I remember moments like this.
I guess back then I didn't realize how important they'd be.
I let times like this slip by without even thinking about them.
This is revival.
It's another chance.
And there's no way I'll let this one slip by.
Mom.
Hmm?
It's really good.
Thank you.
Are you sure you're okay?
Thanks for dinner.
You're welcome.
Am I supposed to do the next 18 years over again?
Morning, Satoru!
Hey, Asamu.
Morning.
If this is revival, then I'm here for one reason.
To stop something bad from happening.
Maybe to save my mom, I have to start here.
But why so far back?
Nothing seems off here.
That's Kaya Hinazuki.
She lived alone with her mom, too.
And bam.
Whoa!
How'd she get that?
You know what I think sucks about this group?
There's no one to talk Dragon Quest with.
Huh?
Uh...
I mean, Hiro's a Final Fantasy fan, and Kazu only plays shooters.
That's Hiro.
And Kazu.
I remember them.
Heck, Satoru doesn't even have a Famicom.
No, I didn't.
Jeez, Asamu.
Oh, if we all played Dragon Quest, then that's all we'd ever talk about.
The cool thing about our group is, we all like different things, so it's never boring.
That's Kenya.
Out of all of us, he was the brainiest.
Can I ask you something, Satoru?
It's kinda personal.
Sure.
Go ahead.
Do you...
have a crush on Kayo?
Huh?
I saw you staring at her.
No way, really?
He totally was.
This morning, he just stood there staring.
He couldn't take his eyes off her.
Dang it, Satoru!
If you're in love with her, you should've come to me for advice.
Romance is right up my alley.
But...
No buts about it.
I'll fix it so you can hook up with Kayo.
Could you keep your voice down?
Why?
Well, it's like...
I don't love her.
Just curious about her.
That's the same thing!
You're brave to admit it!
Don't you worry about a thing!
By the end of the day, you'll be talking with your dream girl!
Ha!
Ah!
You're an idiot.
Damn, she's cold.
That's how you say hello?
I said that out loud.
Oh, crap.
I bet Kazu straight up told her I had a crush on her.
Um, Kayo?
I was thinking, since we walk home the same way, maybe we could be friends?
Friends?
What is it you like about me?
She's a pain in the ass.
You don't have to answer that if you don't want to.
I think I know.
You're just like I am.
You're fake, too.
Wait...
Does she know about me?
I saw you running home yesterday.
Huh?
You looked happy.
Do you love your mom that much?
Yeah.
That's good.
Wait.
Kayo!
Hold up!
So how about it?
You want to be friends?
Are you serious?
So, like...
Does that mean you'd kill to protect me?
No, you don't get it!
I could have saved her!
Something bad was happening to Kayo in the days before she died.
Maybe if I can stop it, I can save her.
I think I know.
You're just like I am.
You're fake, too.
I doubt she could tell I wasn't really a kid.
I guess maybe I might have been acting a little weird,
but that's pretty much how I was back in those days.
I wanted friends,
so I tried acting like the person I wanted to be.
If you have courage, you can do anything.
It was the only way I knew how to fit in in my middle school world.
No.
We were going to send a search party in the house.
I bet she saw through that.
But she said I was like her,
so maybe she's hiding her true self, too.
So, how'd you make out?
Yeah, man.
You gonna tell us how it went or what?
Did you guys walk home together?
Did you hold hands?
Geez, no.
We just talked for a little bit, that's all.
Just you two?
Alone?
Mm-hmm.
Sweet!
That means she totally likes you!
Dude, seriously.
She never talks to anyone alone!
You want me to give her another...
Could they be more annoying?
Take it easy, guys.
Pressuring him like this isn't gonna help him.
You're right.
He's talking about something else, but...
Yeah.
Satoru.
In sixth grade, we'll all be in the same class again.
So there's no rush.
Right.
Attention, students.
When did Kyo disappear again?
Ugh, I'm running out of time.
Satoru, come on!
Yeah, come in!
It's cold.
By the way, where are those kick-ass McGregor gloves you got?
Oh, yeah.
I remember I had a pair of those.
I guess maybe I left him somewhere.
Oh, well, they're probably at the hideout then.
Hey, guys.
Can we go to the hideout today?
What are you talking about?
Remember?
We said we wouldn't go there if it snows,
because everyone would see our tracks.
Oh, we did?
Oh, right.
Yeah.
See you tomorrow.
Later, dudes.
Later.
Bye.
See ya.
Kenya!
Thanks for speaking up.
It's like they were making such a big deal out of it,
I was freaking out.
Yeah, I bet you were.
You don't have to thank me, though.
By the way, about Kyo.
I think it's great you want to get closer to her and all,
but I get the feeling there's something else going on.
I don't mean to be nosy or anything,
but I'm here if you need to talk to someone.
And not just me.
The other guys are, too.
Thanks.
And yeah,
I know everyone's just trying to help.
Kazuh did get Kyo to talk to me after all.
So, want to talk about it?
About what?
About Kyo.
Oh, right.
Did you talk to her?
Yeah, only for a bit.
She even opened up a little by the end.
That's good.
I know you got a lot on your mind,
but I was wondering.
You read the essays yet?
Huh?
No, I haven't.
There are a couple of interesting ones.
You should check them out.
I better go.
See you tomorrow.
See ya.
I bet Kenya was hinting at Kyo's essay being the interesting one in this.
The Town Without Me by Kyo Hinazuki.
When I get bigger,
big enough to go somewhere by myself,
I want to go someplace far away from here.
I want to go to an island.
An island without any people.
An island that doesn't have any pain or sadness on it either.
There are no grown-ups, kids, classmates, or teachers.
Even my mom's not there.
When I feel like I want to climb a tree,
I can climb it.
I'll go for a swim if I want to.
And sleep when I want to.
On the island,
I'll think about what's going on in the town without me.
Kids go to school like nothing's changed.
Grown-ups go to work like nothing's changed.
Mom eats her dinner like nothing's changed.
And when I think about the town without me,
I feel relief more than anything.
All I want is to go far away.
Her essay's a cry for help.
No doubt about it.
I'm home!
Thanks for dinner.
Kenya probably thought I was interested in her
because of the essay.
After reading it,
now I'm even more worried about her.
Hey, Mom?
Yeah, what's up?
For my birthday,
can I invite some friends over?
Mm-hmm.
Sure, but our place is kind of small.
How many friends are we talking?
Not too many.
Just five.
You know,
this is the first time you asked to have a party.
Should I get a big cake?
Yeah.
Thanks, Mom.
I know what I have to do now.
I have to get to know Kaio even better.
I'm gonna do what I didn't the first time.
If I can make her do something different now,
maybe it'll be enough to change her fate.
Maybe it'll change everything.
Hey, you still awake?
You said five.
Did you get yourself a girlfriend?
Alright.
Goodnight, kiddo.
Witch.
I just remembered something.
I didn't show my mom my essay back then
because I knew she'd read it
and see it right into my soul.
What did I write about again?
I'll go on home with great dragon quest.
Me too.
Man, it's snowing again.
No hideout today.
Huh?
Satoru!
Kaio's leaving.
Don't you want to talk to her?
Osamu.
It's okay, Kenya.
It's no big deal.
And thanks, Osamu.
See ya.
Later, dude.
Can you believe how brave he's gotten?
I didn't have to run.
I already knew where I'd find Kaio.
I was pretty sure her mom was hitting her
and if that was true,
she wouldn't be going home right away.
She'd go hang out at the park
until it got darker out.
Before, I just thought she was weird.
Not anymore.
Kaio!
Satoru, what do you think you're doing out here?
I was gonna say the same thing.
I meant what I said.
I want to be friends.
I won't kill anyone.
That's too much.
No, duh.
That was a joke.
I hate dealing with her type.
You know what you're doing, Satoru.
You're just pretending.
Pretending to smile
and being nice
and worrying about people.
But I don't think it's bad or anything.
I can't tell what you're really like.
That sounds funny coming from me.
Everything you said's true.
I am pretending.
I want people to like me.
I want to have friends.
So I asked myself,
what can a loser like me do to have that?
And you know what?
I tried liking everyone and it worked.
It was hard at first,
but after a while,
it got easier.
Yeah.
And like,
the more you do it,
the better the chance it comes true.
The more I talk about it,
the better the chance it'll come true.
It's like deja vu all over again.
To get what you want,
you have to make an effort.
You have to try new things
and keep inspiring yourself.
That's how you change.
Is that what Kaio's doing too?
I can tell she's suffering now.
But unlike me,
she acts like she doesn't care.
Pretending like she can't feel anything at all.
But she's only ten.
She's not strong enough
to change her situation at home.
Hey Kaio,
I brought something for you.
What?
I'm having a birthday party
and I want you to come.
Are you sure it's okay?
I mean,
won't there be tons of people?
Oh, I don't know yet.
But I wanted to give you
the first invitation.
It's on March the 2nd.
Huh?
You're gonna come, right?
Uh-huh.
Hey,
aren't your hands cold?
Huh?
Oh, yeah.
They kinda are.
I had some new gloves,
but I think I lost them.
Take it easy, dude.
You're 29.
Why are you getting all flustered?
Satoru,
are you okay?
Uh-huh.
I mean,
my hands way bigger than yours, huh?
You're an idiot.
Even so,
you seem like you're okay.
It's easy talking to you.
Well,
it's cause I decided
to be honest with you.
I said that out loud.
Wait,
Kaio?
So, um,
see you tomorrow?
She didn't have gloves either,
did she?
Eighteen years ago,
I saw Kaio here,
alone,
and then she disappeared.
If I remember right,
they found her body
after the snow melted.
This time,
I won't leave her
standing here all alone.
This time?
I'm going to save her.
I won't leave her.
cou comprend
yes
yeah
osób
I've been with you in ahead of me
I moved your everything
Let me keep watching
The light piace from looks maybe
I'm waiting in space
My eyes are being put in a hand
The earth is affected by two people
In the town we didn't know
A gleaming hour
I began to see in the sky
君は僕の胸に刻まれた一番深い傷跡のようで 君が笑うこの世界の歌 取り戻すよ